Ernst Philip Boas Papers 1907-1955 Mss.Ms.Coll.10
American Philosophical Society
- Series I: Correspondence, 1907-1955
  - Box: F - I (Box 3)
    - The Independent Citizens Committee of the Arts, Sciences and Professions, 1944
    - Independent Order Brith Abraham, 1947
    - International Association of Industrial Accident Boards and Commissions, 1948
    - Institute of Aviation Medicine, 1953
    - International Rescue Committee, 1950
    - The Interne, 1947-1953
    - The Interne Council of America Lippman, Richard W., 1941
    - Irvington House, 1941-1945
    - Isaac, Lucile, 1949
  - Box: J - Mi, 1922 (Box 4)
    - Jacoboens, H.C.
    - Jacobson, Sheldon A., 1947
    - Janeway, Theodore C., 1914
    - The Jefferson School, 1944
    - Jewish Center Lecture Bureau, 1950
    - Jewish Home for the Aged, 1944
      -See also Ser.III, "Report on the Jewish Home for the Aged"
    - Jewish Sanitarium and Hospital for Chronic Diseases, 1952
    - Jewish Welfare Federation of Detroit, 1944
    - Journal of Gerontology, 1949
    - Journal of Negro Education, 1948-1949
    - The Journal of the American Medical Association, 1948
    - Karelsen, Frank E., Jr., 1950, 1952
    - Karsner, Howard T., 1940
    - Katz, Hyman (Harry), 1954
    - Katz, L.N., 1945
    - Katzive, J.A., 1946
    - Kert, Morley J., 1945-1946
    - Klein, Eugene, 1916
    - Klotz, Arthur P., 1946
    - Knight, Robert P.
    - Koppelman, Harold
    - Krader, Lawrence, 1951
    - Kraus, 1938
    - Kreeger, Morris Harold, 1945
    - Kroeber, Alfred L.
      -See Ser.I, Rukeyser, Muriel
    - Kubie, Lawrence S.
    - Kunstler and Kunstler, 1955
    - Kurtz, Leonard D., 1945
    - La Follette, Robert M., Jr., 1943
    - Lakeside Laboratories, Inc., 1951-1952
    - Lamb, E.Q., 1952
    - Landauer, Walter, 1934, 1936
    - Lasky, S.S., 1948
    - Laurence, William L.
    - Lawton, George, 1950
    - League for Industrial Democracy, Inc., 1951
    - The League for Mental Health, 1945
    - Leavell, Hugh R.
    - Lederle Laboratories Division, 1953
    - Lee, Robert C., 1940
    - Lehman, Herbert H., 1954
    - Leichtentritt, Bruno, 1944
    - Leiter, Louis, 1950
    - Levin, Morton L.
    - Levine, Samuel A.
    - Levy, Hyman, 1947
      - The Workmen's Circle
        -See also Ser.I, Epstein, Frederick H.
        -See also Ser.I, The Workmen's Circle
        -See also Ser.II, Partnership Agreement with Hyman Levy
    - Lewis, Alfred Baker, 1951
    - Lewis, Mary E., 1945
    - Lewis, Roger A., 1949
    - Lewis, Thomas, 1923
    - Lexington Hospital, 1946
    - Lian, Camille, 1945?
      in French
    - Libman, E., 1925-1937
    - Liebowitz, Benjamin, 1943, 1950, 1954
    - Life Extension Institute, Inc., 1945
    - Lippman, Richard W., 1952
      - Abowitz, Murray
      - Pennes, Alexander E.
        -See also Ser.I, The Interne Council of America
    - Little, Brown and Company, 1952
    - Loewi, Otto, 1939
      -See also Ser.VI, Loewi, Otto
    - Lomzer Aid Society, 1939
    - Long Beach Hospital, Inc., 1942-1955
    - Look, 1944-1945
    - McCoy, Ira Dean, 1951
    - Macfarlane, Helen G., 1940
    - Mackay, Roland P.
    - The Macmillan Company, 1929, 1934, 1951
    - Madison House, 1948
    - Magus-Levy, Adolf, 1944-1956
      -See also Ser.I, Emergency Committee in Aid of Displaced Foreign Medical Scientists
    - Makover, Henry B.
    - Marine, David, 1930
    - Matlin, Saul, 1946
    - Mattingly, Thomas E., 1948
    - Mayer, Barbara, 1945
    - Mayer, Leo, 1951
    - Medical Administration Service, Inc., 1940-1945
    - Medical Care, 1940-1944
    - Medical Society of the County of New York, 1941-1954
    - Menaker, Walter, 1951
    - Mendlowitz, Milton, 1941-1942
      - The Mount Sinai Hospital
    - Menendez, Joseph C.
    - Menninger, Karl A., 1944
    - Metropolitan Life Insurance Company Meyer, Benard C., 1934
    - Meyer, Joseph C., 1949-1950
    - Michigan State Medical Society, 1953
    - Michigan Unemployment Compensation Commission, 1944
    - Miller, Louis
      -See Ser.I, Barsky, Edward K.
  - Box: Mo - New York He (Box 5)
    - Montefiore Hospital for Chronic Diseases, 1920-1938
    - Moosehaven, 1948-1954
    - Morgan, Hugh J., 1950
      - Butler, Allan M.
    - Morris County Medical Society, 1941
    - The Mount Sinai Hospital, 1920-1952
      - Baehr, George
        -See also Ser.I, Mendlowitz, Milton
        -See also Ser.II, The Mount Sinai Hospital
    - Muller, Hermann J., 1941
    - Murray, D. Stark, 1950
    - Murray, James E., 1948
    - Muslin, Ben, 1952
    - The Nation Associates, 1944-1950
    - National Association for the Advancement of Colored People, 1944
    - National Association of Claimants' Compensation Attorneys, 1948-1953
    - National Association of Colored Graduate Nurses, Inc., 1947
    - National CIO Community Services Committee, 1949
    - National Citizens Political Action Committee, 1944
    - National Committee for Resettlement of Foreign Physicians, 1944-1954
      -See also Ser.VI, same title
    - National Committee to Combat Anti-Semitism, 1943
    - National Conference on Health and Medical Care, 1938
    - National Council of the Arts, Sciences and Professions, 1948
      - Shapley, Harlow
    - National Health Assembly
      -See Ser.I and II, United States. Federal Security Agency
    - National Medical Association, Inc., 1948
    - National Newspaper Service, 1947
    - National Physicians Committee
      -See Ser.I, Oxnam, G. Bromley
    - National Refugee Service, Inc., 1943
    - National Women's Trade Union League of America, 1949
    - Neuburger, Fritz, 1938
    - Neumann, Rudolf, 1943
      some in German
    - The New England Journal of Medicine, 1950
    - New Jersey Heart Association, 1949
    - The New School, 1953
    - The New York Academy of Medicine, 1944, 1947
      - Baehr, George
        -See also Oversized
    - New York Cardiac Home, Inc., 1951, 1954
    - New York City. Board of Education, 1934, 1946
    - The New York City Cancer Committee, 1934
    - New York City. Committee on Discrimination in Medical Institutions, 1948
    - New York City. Department of Health, 1928-1954
    - New York City. Department of Hospitals, 1934-1935
    - New York Guild for the Jewish Blind, 1938-1952
    - New York Heart Association, Inc.
      - Cohn, Alfred E.
        - Folder #1, 1934-1944
        - Folder #2, 1945-1947
        - Folder #3, 1948-1949
  - Box: New York Ho - Sa (Box 6)
    - New York Homeopathic Medical College and Flower Hospital, 1919-1920
    - The New York Hotel Trades Council and Hotel Association, 1950-1952
    - New York Medicine, 1948, 1952
    - New York State. Department of Health, 1940-1942
    - New York State Health Preparedness Commission, 1944, 1946
    - New York State Joint Legislative Committee on Problems of the Aging, 1949-1954
      - Crampton, C. Ward
        -See also Ser.II, New York State Joint Legislative Committee on Problems of the Aging
    - New York State Society for Medical Research, 1951
    - The New York Times, 1951
    - New York Tuberculosis and Health Association, 1933-1934, 1943
    - Non-Governmental Organizations Interested in Migration, 1953-1954
    - Norwalk (Connecticut) Town Hall Association, 1945
    - Optical Membership Plan, Inc., 1944-1952
    - Orthodox Jewish Home for the Aged, 1953
    - Oxnam, G. Bromley, 1949
    - Pacini, August J., 1951
    - Pardee, Harold E.B., 1945
    - Parets, Albert D., 1950
    - Park, E.A., 1947
    - Parmenter, Richard, 1940
    - Parran, Thomas, 1939
    - Patterson, F.D.
    - Pauling, Linus
    - Pease, Marshall C.
    - Pennes, Alexander E.
    - Pepper, Claude, 1942
      -See also Ser.I, United States Senate. Committee on Education and Labor. Subcommittee on Wartime Health and Education
    - Perry, Thomas L.
    - Peters, John P., 1947-1955
      - Young, Edward L.
        -See also Ser.I, Butler, Allan M.
    - Peterson, Jerome S.
    - The Physicians Forum, Inc., 1941-1955
      - Aschner, Bernard
      - Blanchard, James A.
      - Boernstein, Walter S.
      - Braun, Edmund
      - Butler, Allan M.
      - Cannon, George D.
      - Cobb, W. Montague
      - Davidoff, Leo M.
      - Davis, Michael M., 1947
      - Elliott, Martha
      - Ewing, Oscar R.
      - Gottlieb, Abraham
      - Gregg, Alan
      - Hook, John P.
      - Makover, Henry B.
      - Mayer, Leo
      - Sanders, Theodore
      - Sloane, Paul
      - Smith, H. Alexander
      - Stern, Alfred K.
      - Pease, Marshall C.
      - Peters, John P.
      - Peterson, Jerome S.
      - Roemer, Milton I.
      - Warburg, Bettina
      - Wiener, Herbert J.
      - Young, Edward L.
        -See also Ser.I, New York Medicine
        -See also Ser.II, The Physicians Forum, Inc.
    - Pottenger, F.M.
    - The President's Commission on the Health Needs of the Nation, 1952
      - Breslow, Lester
    - Progressive Citizens of America, 1947
      - Shapley, Harlow
    - Pullen, Roscoe L., 1947-1950
    - Putnam, Herbert, n.d.
    - Putnam, Tracy Jackson, 1947
    - Radack, Herbert, 1950
    - Radbill, Samuel X., 1952
    - Radin, Theodore, 1936
    - Raider, Leonard J., 1949
    - Rare Chemicals, Inc., 1936
    - Richardson, Henry B.
    - Ringer, Carl, 1954
    - The Rockefeller Foundation, 1942
    - Roemer, Milton I., 1946-1955
    - Rogoff, Julius M., 1954
    - Roosevelt, Eleanor, 1951
    - Ros, Arturo R., 1952-1954
    - The Benjamin Rose Institute, 1944
      - Wagner, Margaret W.
    - Roth, Irving R., 1943
    - Rukeyser, Muriel, 1947-1953, n.d.
      - Kroeber, Alfred L.
    - Saint Peter's General Hospital, 1949
    - Salk, Jonas E., 1953
    - Sanders, Theodore
  - Box: Sc - Wa (Box 7)
    - Scheinfeld, Amram, 1950
    - Schick, Bela
    - Schlesinger, Monroe J., 1948
    - Schlippenbach, Luise Gräfin, 1950
    - Schreiber, Walter P., 1952
    - Seham, Max
    - Shapley, Harlow, 1948-[1949]
      - Binger, Carl
        -See also Ser.I, Binger, Carl
        -See also Ser.I, Hugh Cabot Memorial Fund, Inc.
        -See also Ser.I, Hook, Sidney
        -See also Ser.I, National Council of the Arts, Sciences and Professions
        -See also Ser.I, Progressive Citizens of America
    - Sigerist, Henry E., 1941-1947
    - Sigall, Harold N., n.d.
    - Silberman, David E., 1949
    - Simon, John L., 1953
      - Group Health Insurance, Inc.
    - Simonoff, Lewis, 1948
    - Singer, Edward, 1952
    - Sloane, Paul
    - Smillie, W.G., 1945, 1947
    - Smith, G.M., 1949
    - Smith, H. Alexander
    - Social Planning Council of Saint Louis, 1944-1945
    - The Society for Ethical Culture, 1944, 1949
    - Spanish Embassy, 1939
    - Sperry, Joseph Evans, 1928
    - State University of New York, 1949
    - Stecher, Robert M., 1948-1949
    - Steele, J. Murray, 1948
      - Crampton, C. Ward
    - Steinberg, Arthur G., 1952, n.d.
    - Stephens, Roger, 1950
    - Stern, Alfred K.
    - Stern, Kurt G., 1954
    - Strachstein, Abraham, 1954
    - Stricker, Jenny, 1949
    - Strone, Bernard, 1954
    - Swetlow, George, 1955
    - Swiont, Marjan S., 1954
    - The Sydenham Institute of Community Relations, 1947
    - Teleky, Ludwig, 1948
    - Trubenizing Process Corporation, 1945
    - Ungerleider, Harry E., 1953
    - Unidentified, 1923-1955, n.d.
    - United Electrical, Radio and Machine Workers of America, 1944, 1949
    - United HIAS Service, 1954
      -See also Ser.I, United Service for New Americans, Inc.
    - United Service for New Americans, Inc., 1947-1953
      -See also Ser.I, United HIAS Service
    - United States. Department of Labor., 1951-1955
      - Bureau of Employees Compensation
    - United States. Federal Security Agency, 1941-1951
      - Falk, I.S.
      - Weinerman, E. Richard
        -See also Ser.II, United States. Federal Security Agency
    - United States. Office of Civilian Requirements, 1943
    - United States Public Health Service, 1935-1936, 1952
    - United States Senate. Committee on Banking and Currency, 1944
    - United States Senate. Committee on Education and Labor. Subcommittee on Wartime Health and Education Pepper, Claude, 1944-1945
    - United States. Veterans Administration, 1948, 1952
    - United States. War Department, 1918
      -See also Ser.III, "Cases of Effort Syndrome Studied at Camp McClellan, Alabama"
    - United States. War Production Board, 1943
    - Urbach, Rudolf, 1936
    - Vermilye, Herbert N., 1939
    - Von den Steinen, Helmut, 1948-1949
    - Wagner, Margaret W., 1952
      -See also Ser.I, The Benjamin Rose Institute
    - Wagner, Robert F.
    - Wallace, H.A., 1945
    - Warburg, Bettina, 1944, 1950
      -See also Ser.I, Wendriner, Herbert
    - Warburg, James P.
    - Washburn, Alfred H.
    - Washington Institute of Medicine, 1950
    - Weinerman, E. Richard, 1949
    - Weiss, Morris M., 1949
    - Welfare Council of New York City, 1934-1943
      -See also Ser.III, "Memorandum on the Desirability of Developing Welfare Island for the Care of the Chronic Sick"
    - Wendriner, Herbert, 1948-1952
      - Warburg, Bettina
    - Wenk, Eugene Lloyd, 1945
    - The Western Political Quarterly, 1951
  - Box: Wh - Z (Box 8)
    - White, Abraham, 1951
    - White, Paul Dudley, 1945
    - The Walt Whitman Society of America, 1952
    - Wick, Homer C., Jr., 1953
    - Wiener, Herbert J.
    - William, Maurice, 1948
    - The Williams and Wilkins Company, 1953
    - Wilson, J. Finley, 1948
    - Winard, Arthur I., 1952-1954
    - Wise, Christine, 1950
    - The Workmen's Circle, 1930-1954
      - Levy, Hyman
        -See also Ser.I, Levy, Hyman
        -See also Ser.II, The Workmen's Circle
    - Yale Law Journal, 1952-1953
    - Yampolsky, Helene, 1938, 1957
    - The Year Book Publishers, Inc., 1941-1953
    - Young, Edward L.
      -See Ser.I, Committee of Physicians for the Improvement of Medical Care, Inc.
      -See Ser.I, Peters, John P.
    - Zimmerman, Robert L., 1954
- Series II: Subject Files, 1914-1955
  Meeting minutes and reports for various organizations with which Boas was affiliated, including the American Heart Association, the Committee of Physicians for the Improvement of Medical Care, Inc., the Commission on Chronic Illness, the Sidney Hillman Health Center, the Medical Society of the County of New York, the Montefiore Hospital for Chronic Diseases, The Mount Sinai Hospital, the National Committee for Resettlement of Foreign Physicians, the New York Heart Association, Inc., The Physicians Forum, Inc., and the Welfare Council of New York City. The material about The Physicians Forum, Inc. includes congratulatory letters (about the organization and about Boas's leadership of it) written on its tenth anniversary in 1953.
  There are copies of Boas's book plate (with an identification of the Egyptian hieroglyphs on it); copies of Boas's business card; a copy of Boas's partnership agreement with Hyman Levy; copies of Boas's income tax returns (federal and New York state) from 1919 to 1947; a description of Boas's medical history from 1928 to 1955; and a copy of Boas's death certificate. Also in this series are reviews of some of Boas's books, including Coronary Artery Disease, Treatment of the Patient Past Fifty, and The Unseen Plague--Chronic Disease; notebooks containing Boas's expenses from 1918 to 1945; clippings regarding chronic illness and national health insurance; programs for lectures; information about Boas's cardiotachometer; court testimonies (for compensation hearings) that Boas gave regarding the conditions of people who had died while doing strenuous labor; a prospectus for the Journal of Social Medicine; and Boas's bibliography, as well as the bibliography of his son, Norman F. Boas.
  - Box: A - Bi (Box 8)
    - Add Life to Your Years-- Reviews, 1953-1954
    - The American Board of Internal Medicine
      -See Oversized
    - American Heart Association, 1946-1953, n.d.
      -See also Ser.I, same title
    - American Medical Association, 1942-1951
      -See also Ser.I, The New York Times
    - American Public Health Association, [194-]
    - American Public Welfare Association, 1939
    - The American Society for Clinical Investigation, 1935, 1950, 1953
    - The American Society for the Study of Arteriosclerosis, 1948, n.d.
    - Association of Internes and Medical Students, [194-]
    - The Authors Guild, 1953
    - Bibliographical References to Boas' Work, 1944, [194-], 1951
    - Bibliography--Ernst P. Boas, [194-]; 3 folders
    - Bibliography--Norman F. Boas, [1954]
  - Box: Bo - Com (Box 9)
    - Book Plate, n.d.
      -See also Ser.I, Horine, Emmet P., 16 May 1945
    - Bronx Tuberculosis and Health Committee, 1929-1930
    - Business Card--Ernst P. Boas, n.d.
    - Cardiac Injury Resulting from Effort or Trauma-- Rejections, 1952-1954
    - Cardiotachometer
      -See also Ser.I, Harvey, Samuel C.
      -See also Ser.I, Landauer, Walter
      -See also Ser.I, Lee, Robert C.
      -See also Ser.I, Parmenter, Richard
      -See also Ser.I, Wick, Homer C., Jr.
      -See also Ser.VI, Cardiotachometer
      -See also Ser.VII, Cardiotachometer
      - Folder #1, 1927-1934
      - Folder #2, 1936-1937
    - Chronic Illness, 1924-1945
    - Clippings, 1917-1953, n.d.
    - Clippings--Index, 1924-1955
    - Collection of Plant Specimens
    - Columbia University
      - Folder #1, 1915-1937
      - Folder #2, 1947-1954
    - Commission on Chronic Illness
      - Folder #1, 1949-1952
      - Folder #2, 1953, n.d.
    - Committee for the Nation's Health, 1946-1950
    - Committee of One Thousand, 1931, 1948
    - Committee of Physicians for the Improvement of Medical Care, Inc., 1940-1950, n.d.
    - Committee on Un-American Activities, 1947-1948
  - Box: Con - Hillman #2, 1948 (Box 10)
    - Conference on Pattern for Survival
      -See also Ser.III, "The Probable Effects of Another World War on the Health of the People"
    - "Conversion of Public Homes for the Aged and Dependent into Institutions for the Care of the Sick", 30 Mar. 1939
    - Coronary Artery Disease-- Reviews, 1949-1950
    - The Council for Heart Diseases, Inc., 1946
    - Court Testimonies Regarding Cardiac Conditions, 1929-1954
    - Death Certificate of Ernst Boas, 1955
    - Emergency Committee in Aid of Displaced Foreign Medical Scientists, 1943-1954, n.d.
    - Ethical Culture School--Diploma
    - Expenses--Notebook #1, 1918-1920
    - Expenses--Notebook #2, 1924-1929
    - Expenses #3, 1928-1945
    - Group Health Insurance, Inc., 1944-1951, n.d.
    - Health Insurance (National)
      - Folder #1, 1939-1944
      - Folder #2, 1945-Mar. 1949
      - Folder #3, Apr. 1949-1952, n.d.
    - "Heart"--Word Derivations, n.d.
    - The Sidney Hillman Health Center
      - Folder #1, 1948-Feb. 1953
      - Folder #2, Mar. 1953-1954
  - Box: Hillman #3 - M (Box 11)
    - The Sidney Hillman Health Center (cont.)
      - Folder #3, 1955, n.d.
    - The Hudson Guild, 1920
    - The Home for Aged and Infirm Hebrews, 1937, n.d.
    - Income Tax Returns--Federal, 1920-1947
    - Income Tax Returns--New York State, 1919-1943
    - The Independent Citizens Committee of the Arts, Sciences and Professions, 1951
    - Journal of Social Medicine, 1947
    - McCosker-Hershfield Cardiac Foundation, Inc., 1937, 1953
    - Medical History of Ernst P. Boas, 1928-1955
    - Medical Society of the County of New York, 1939-1954, n.d.
    - Montefiore Hospital for Chronic Diseases, 1928-1934
    - Moosehaven, 1949-1952
    - The Mount Sinai Hospital, 1944-1952
  - Box: N - Pa (Box 12)
    - National Committee for Resettlement of Foreign Physicians, 1945-1954, n.d.
    - National Physicians' Committee for the Extension of Medical Service, 1939, n.d.
    - The New York Academy of Medicine--Membership Certificate
    - New York City. Department of Health, 1947-1949, n.d.
    - New York Guild for the Jewish Blind, 1938-1946, n.d.
    - New York Heart Association, Inc.
      - Folder #1, 1935-1944
      - Folder #2, 1945-1949
      - Folder #3, 1949-1951, n.d.
    - New York Hotel Trades Council and Hotel Association
    - New York State Health Preparedness Commission, 1944, 1949, n.d.
    - New York State Joint Legislative Committee on Problems of the Aging, 1953
    - New York Tuberculosis and Health Association, 1936
    - New York World's Fair. Advisory Committee on Medicine and Public Health--Certificate
    - Non-Governmental Organizations Interested in Migration, 1953-1954, n.d.
    - Optical Membership Plan, Inc., 1947-1948
    - Partnership Agreement with Hyman Levy, Jun. 1949
  - Box: Ph - Welfare #1 (Box 13)
    - The Physicians Forum, Inc., 1942-1957, n.d.
    - The Physicians Forum, Inc. Tenth
      - Anniversary Dinner
        - Bernheim, Bertram M.
        - Binger, Carl
        - Black, Algernon D.
        - Bohr, Niels
        - Brown, Charlotte Hawkins
        - Butler, Allan M.
        - Cobb, Stanley
        - Cohn, Alfred E.
        - Committee for Medical Freedom
        - Cornely, Paul B.
        - Crohn, Burrill B.
        - Cross, Frank E.
        - Deutsch, Albert
        - Dodd, Katharine
        - Dodd, Martha; Stern, Alfred K.
        - Enzer, Norbert
        - Feuchtwanger, Lion
        - France, Royal Wilbur
        - Frichtman, Stephen H.
        - Gordon, A.M.
        - Gordon, Asher T.
        - Hamilton, Alice
        - Harper, Fowler V.
        - Hollander, Louis
        - Knight, Robert P.
        - Koppelman, Harold
        - Kubie, Lawrence S.
        - Leavell, Hugh R.
        - Leiter, Louis
        - Mackay, Roland P.
        - Mayer, Leo
        - Menendez, Joseph C.
        - Menninger, Karl A.
        - Meyer, Bernard C.
        - Meyer, Joseph C.
        - Patterson, F.D.
        - Pauling, Linus
        - Perry, Thomas L.
        - Peters, John P.
        - Pottenger, F.M.
        - Richardson, Henry B.
        - Roemer, Milton I.
        - Roosevelt, Eleanor
        - Schick, Bela
        - Seham, Max
        - Sigerist, Henry E.
        - Steele, J. Murray
        - Warburg, James P.
        - Washburn, Alfred H.
        - Weinerman, E. Richard
        - Young, Edward L.
          -See also Ser.III, The Physicians
        - Forum, Inc. Tenth Anniversary
        - 20 Feb. 1953, 2 folders
    - Pi Gamma Mu Honor Society--Membership Certificate
    - Prescription Pad, n.d.
    - Programs, 1950-1953
    - Quotes, n.d.
    - Register of Physicians and Surgeons--Certificates, 1914, 1917
    - Social Security
      -See Ser.II, Temporary Committee for the Organization of a Social Security Campaign
    - The Society for Ethical Culture
      - Folder #1, 1916
      - Folder #2, 1926, n.d.
    - The Sydenham Institute of Community Relations, 1947
    - Temporary Committee for the Organization of a Social Security Campaign, 1944
    - Tentants' Protective Committee of 1185 Park Avenue, 1949
    - Treatment of the Patient Past Fifty-- Review and Advertisment, [1947]
    - United Hias Service, 1955
    - United States Army--Honorable Discharge Certificate, 24 May 1919
    - United States Committee, Inc., 1948
    - United States. Federal Security Agency, 1948; 2 folders
    - The Unseen Plague--Chronic Disease-- Review, 1940
    - Welfare Council of New York City
      - Folder #1, 1934-1937
  - Box: Welfare #2 - Wo (Box 14)
    - Welfare Council of New York City (cont.)
      - Folder #2, 1938-1941
      - Folder #3, 1942-1943, n.d.
    - The Workmen's Circle, n.d.
- Series III: Works by Boas, 1907-1955